Hi everyone, here is my solution for the transfer learning exercise that I had to do.
现在说说上道练习的答案
So, this one's going to be a little different.
这次我将采用不同的讲解方式
I'm going to be typing it out as I do it so you can understand
我将一边输入代码一边讲解
my that process is kind of the combination of everything you've learned in this lesson.
实际上是将在这节课所学的所有知识结合到了一起
So, the first thing I'm going do is,
首先
if I have a GPU available,
如果我有 GPU
I'm going to write this code in agnostic way so that I can use the GPU.
我将先询问 GPU 设备是否可用
So, what I'm going to say, device = torch.device and then this is going to be cuda.
输入 device = torch.device 在这里添加 cuda
So, it's going to run on our GPU if torch.cuda is available, else CPU.
If torch.cuda.is_available() else “cpu”
So, what this will do is,
这行代码的作用是
if our GPU is available,
如果 GPU 可用
then this will be true and then we'll return cuda here and then otherwise, it'll be CPU.
这个将为 True 在这里返回 cuda 否则返回 CPU
So, now we can just pass device to all the tensors and models and then it
现在我们可以将 device 传递给所有张量和模型
will just automatically go to the GPU if we have it available.
如果 GPU 可用 则自动使用 GPU
So, next, I'm going to get our pre-trained model.
接下来获取预训练的模型
So, here I'm actually going to use ResNet.
我将使用 ResNet
So, to do this, model dot models.
输入 model = models
So, we already imported models from
我们已经从 torchvision 导入 models
torch vision then we can kind of like took out all the ones they have.
菜单中列出了所有模型
So, there's ResNet there.
ResNet 在这里
So, I'm just going to use a fairly small one,
我将使用很小的模型 选择 resnet50
ResNet 50 and then we want pre-trained true and that should get us our model.
输入 pretrained=True 这样应该就能获得该模型
So, now if we look,
好了
so we can just print it out like this and it
像这样输出模型
will tell us all the different operations and layers and everything that's going on.
就会显示出所有不同的操作和层级等
So, if we scroll down, we can see that at the end here has fc.
向下滚动到末尾 可以看到这个 fc
So, this is the last layer,
表示最后一层
this fully connected layer that's acting like a classifier.
是一个充当分类器的全连接层
So, we can see that it has,
它要求这层输入为 2,048 个单元
it expects 2,048 inputs to this layer and then the out features are 1,000.
输出为 1,000 个单元
So, remember that this was trained on ImageNet and so ImageNet
这个模型是用 ImageNet 训练的
is typically trained with 1,000 different classes of images.
ImageNet 用有 1,000 个不同类别的图像训练而成
But here we're only using cat and dog,
但是我们只使用猫和狗图像
so we just need to output features and in our classifier.
因此这个分类器只需 2 个输出单元
So, we can load the model like that and now I'm going to make sure
我们可以加载这样的模型
that our models' perimeters are frozen
确保在训练模型时冻结模型参数
so that when we're training they don't get updated.
这样就不会更新这些参数
So, I'll just run this make sure it works.
运行这部分代码 看看是否没有任何问题
So, now, we can load the model and we can turn off gradients.
现在加载模型并关闭梯度
Turn off gradients for our model.
关闭模型的梯度
So, then, the next step is we want to
下一步是
define our new classifier which we will be training.
定义新分类器
So, here, we can make it pretty simple.
这一步可以很简单
So, models= nn.sequential.
输入 models= nn.sequential
You can define this in a lot of different ways,
用很多不同的定义方式可以用
so I'm just using an industrial sequential here.
我使用 nn.sequential
So, our first layer, so linear,
第一个层级是线性层级
so remember we needed 248 inputs and then let's say,
我们需要 248 个输入
let's drop it down to 512 at a ReLu layer, a dropout.
缩减到 512 个 添加 ReLu 层、丢弃层
Now our output layer,
然后是输出层
512 to two and then we're going to do log softmax.
512 到 2 调用 LogSoftmax
I should change this to be a classifier.
应该将这个改为 classifier.
Okay. So, that's to finding our classifier and now we can attach it to our model,
Ok.定义好 classifier 将其附加到模型上
so to say, model.fc= classifier.
输入 model.fc= classifier
Now, if we look at our model again,
再次查看模型
so we can scroll down to the bottom here.
向下滚动到底部
So, we see now this fully-connected module layer
可以看出现在这个全连接层是一个序列分类器
here is a sequential classifier linear operation ReLu,
这里是线性操作 然后是 ReLu
dropout, another linear transformation and then log softmax.
丢弃层 另一个线性转换 然后是 log softmax
So, the next thing we do is define my loss, my criterion.
接下来定义损失/条件
So, this is going to be the negative log like we had loss.
设为负对数似然损失
Then, define our optimizer, optim.Adam.
然后定义优化器 等于 optim.Adam
So, we want to use the parameters from
我们想使用分类器中的参数
our classifier which is fc here and then set our learning rate.
分类器是这个 fc 然后设置学习速率
The final thing to do is to move our model to whichever device we have available.
最后一步是将模型移到可用的设备上
So, now we have the model all set up and it's time to train it.
设置好模型后 现在开始训练模型
Here's is the first thing I'm going to do is define
首先我将定义一些
some variables that we're going to be using during the training.
将在训练过程中使用的变量
So, for example, I'm going to set our epochs, so I'm going to set to one.
例如我将周期设为 1
I'll be tracking the number of train steps we do,
跟踪训练步数
so set that to zero.
设为 0
I'll be tracking our loss,
跟踪损失
so also set this to zero, and finally,
也设为 0
we want to kind of set a loop for
最后设置一个循环
how many steps we're going to go before we print out the validation loss.
表示在输出验证损失之前训练多少步
So, now we want to loop through our epochs.
遍历周期
So, for epoch and range epochs.
for epoch in range(epochs)
Now, we're going to loop through our data for images,
遍历图像数据
labels in trainloader, cumulate steps.
for images, labels in trainloader
So, basically, every time we go through one of these batches,
递增步数 每次经过一个批次
we're going to increment steps here.
步数都递增
So, now that we have our images and our labels,
现在已经获得图像和标签
we're going to want to move them over to the GPU, if that's available.
如果有 GPU 则将它们移到 GPU 上
So, we're just going to do is images.to (device), labels.to(device).
= images.to(device), labels.to(device)
Now we're just going to write out our training loop.
现在编写训练循环
So, the first thing we need to do is zero our gradients.
首先清零梯度
So, it's very important, don't forget to do this.
这是很重要的步骤 一定不要忘记了
Then, get our log probabilities from our model,
然后从模型中获取对数概率
model passed in the images with the log probabilities,
传入 images 获得对数概率后
we can get our loss from the criterion in the labels.
我们可以从 criterion 获取损失 传入 labels
Then do a backwards pass and then finally with our optimizer we take a step.
然后执行反向传播 最后执行优化器步骤
Here, we can increment are running loss like so.
递增 running_loss
So, this way we can keep track of our training loss as we are
这样的话 当我们用越来越多的数据训练模型后
going through more and more data. All right.
可以跟踪训练损失好了
So, that is the training loop.
这就是训练循环
So, now every once in a while so which is set by this like print every variable.
我们希望每隔一段时间输出结果 即这个 print_every 变量
We actually want to drop out of the train loop and test
现在 我们要退出训练循环
our network's accuracy and loss on our test dataset.
使用测试数据集测试网络的准确率和损失
So, for step modulo print_every,
输入 for step %% print_every == 0:
this is equal to zero, then we're going to go into our validation loop.
如果等于 0 则进入验证循环
So, what we need to do first is set model.eval.
首先调用 model.eval
So, this'll turn our model into evaluation inference mode which turns off dropout.
将模型变成评估推理模式 这样会关闭丢弃
So, we can actually accurately use our network for making
从而准确地使用网络做出预测
predictions instead a test loss and accuracy.
设置测试损失和准确率
So, now we'll get our images and labels from our test data.
从测试数据中获取图像和标签
Now we'll do our validation loop.
执行验证循环
So, with our model so we'll pass in the images.
向模型中传入图像
So, these are the images from our test set.
这些图像来自测试集
So, we're going to get our logps from our test set so again,
从测试集获取 logps
get the loss with our criterion and keep track of our loss to test loss plus+= loss.item.
通过 criterion 获取损失 输入 test_loss += loss.item() 来跟踪损失
So, this will allow us to keep
这样 在经过这些验证循环时
track of our test loss as we're going through these validation rules.
可以跟踪测试损失
So, next we want to calculate our accuracy.
接下来计算准确率
So, probabilities= torch.exponential(logps).
Ps = torch.exp(logps)
So, remember that our model is returning log softmax,
模型返回的是 log softmax
so it's the log probabilities of our classes and to get the actual probabilities,
表示类别的对数概率
we're going to use torch.exponential.
要获取实际概率 我们将使用 torch.exp
So we get our top probabilities and top classes from ps.topk(1).
top_ps, top_class = ps.topk(1)
So, that's going to give us our first largest value in our probabilities.
获得最大概率
Here, we need to make sure we set dimension to one to make sure it's actually like
将维度设为 1
looking for the top probabilities along the columns.
这样可以确保沿着列查找最高概率
Go to the top classes,
获得最高概率后
now we can check for equality with our labels and then with the equality tensor,
检查是否和标签匹配
we can update our accuracy.
根据 equality 张量更新 accuracy
So, here remember we can calculate our accuracy from equality.
我们可以从 equality 计算 accuracy
Once we change it to a FloatTensor then we can do
更改为浮点数张量后
torch.mean and get our accuracy and so again just
就可以运行torch.mean 并获得 accuracy
kind of incremented accumulated into this accuracy variable. All right.
递增这个 accuracy 变量好了
Now, we are in this loop here so this four step every print_every.
现在我们位于这个 for 循环里 for step %% print_every
So basically, now we have a running loss of our training loss and we have
获得训练损失 running_loss 和测试损失 test_loss
a test loss that we passed our test data through
将测试数据传入模型中
our model and measured the loss in accuracy.
并衡量损失和准确率
So now we can print all this out
现在输出所有这些结果
and I'm just going to copy and paste this because it's a lot to type.
直接复制粘贴这段代码 手动输入的话 代码太多了
So, basically here, we're just printing out our epochs.
在这里输出 epochs
So, we can keep track and know where we are and keep track of that.
不断跟踪进度
So, running_loss divided by print_every so basically we're
用 running_loss 除以 print_every
taking the average of our training loss.
对训练损失取平均值
So every time we print it out,
每次输出时
we're just going to take the average.
都会取平均值
Then, test_loss over length the testloader.
用 test_loss 除以 testloader 的长度
So basically length test loader tells us how many batches
len(testloader) 表示
are actually in our test dataset that we're getting from testloader.
我们从 testloader 获得了多少批数据
So, since we're we're summing up all the losses for each of our batches,
因为我们对每批的损失求和
if we take the total loss and divide by
所以 如果用总损失除以批次数量
the number of batches and that gives us our average loss,
就能得出平均损失
we do the same thing with accuracy.
准确率也一样
So, we're summing up the accuracy for each batch here and then we just divide
对每个批次的准确率求和
by the total number of batches and that gives us our average accuracy for the test set.
然后除以批次数量 得出测试集的平均准确率
Then at the end,
最后
we can set our running loss back to
将 running_loss 设为 0
zero and then we also want to put our model back into training mode.
并将模型设为训练模式
Great. So, that should be the training code and we'll see if it works.
好了这些就是训练代码 看看能否运行
Now, this should be an if instead of a for.
这里应该是 if 而不是 for
So, here I forgot this happens a lot.
这里我忘记将张量转移到 GPU 上了
I forgot to transfer my tensors over to the GPU.
这种情况很常见
So, hopefully this will work. All right.
希望能运行好的
So, even like pretty quickly,
测试准确率超过了 95%
we see that we can actually get our test accuracy on this above 95 percent.
甚至速度很快
So, this is, remember that we're printing this out
我们每隔五个周期都输出结果
every five steps and so this is a total of 15 batches,
因此总共 15 个批次
training batches that were updated in the model.
我们用 15 批数据训练了模型
So, we're able to easily fine tune these classifiers on
太好了 我们学习了如何轻松地调整这些分类器
top and get greater than a 95 percent accuracy on our dataset.
并在数据集上获得超过 95% 的准确率